# 这道菜自从我们更了教学之后很多人都去做
Since we posted a tutorial of this dish, many people have attempted
# 但是我看了一下
However, as I checked it
# 目前为止没有哪个说做得很好
There is no one who cooked well so far.
# 都是做得要么就是珊瑚短了
Either the coral was made too short,
# 要么就是歪了
Or skewed.
# 如果说要把这个珊瑚切条
If we want to slice it into coral strips,
# 这上面这片必定要把它切长
This slice must be cut long enough.
# 切这么长就够了
Being this long should be enough.
# 所以在这个地方下刀是比较适合的
So, it's better to start slicing from here
# 而且这个不能切太薄知道吧
And don't slice it too thinly, you know
# 鱼片切薄了
If we slice too thinly,
# 你等一下你腌味上粉的时候
When you marinate and starch it later,
# 一下就断了
it's going to break.
# 好 继续
Ok, let's move on.
# 看 出来了
Look!
# 我们可以边看这个
We can keep watching it closely
# 然后拿起来看一下行了 赶紧停下来
And then pick it up and check: "OK, it's good, stop right here!"
# 不要再切了再切就断了
Don’t cut any further, or it's cut through
# 其实做菜一定要对自己有信心
Actually, you must be confident in yourself when cooking
# 从第一片开始
Start from the first slice.
# 如果你们第一次切的话
If this is your first time to do it
# 这个鱼片下来放在冰箱平放
After filleting, put it in a refrigerator flatwise
# 下面应该是平放 放冰箱冻40分钟
Flatwise and freeze for 40 minutes.
# 成不成功就看这个鱼片
Whether it's successful or not depends on the fish fillet.
# 这个鱼啊我们切出来之后一定要去洗一下
After cutting, the fish must be rinsed
# 因为这个鱼是新鲜的鱼
Because it's a fresh fish
# 它肯定是会有一些血沫啊
There's some blood and scum for sure
# 轻轻挤一下 轻轻捏一下
Squeeze gently. Press gently.
# 用力一捏这个鱼就废了
If you press too hard, the fish is wasted.
# 有一点就行 它主要起到一个效果就行了
You just need to add a little bit. To make it effective
# 淀粉一定要慢慢的加
Starch must be added in slowly
# 不要一下子倒进去
Do not pour all of it at once
# 因为淀粉加到它够了就行了
Because, as long as there's enough starch, it's good enough
# 知道吧
You know?
# 加多了没用
It's useless to add too much
# 你加多的话全都是浪费
If you add too much, it's all wasted
# 我们加的时候啊
When we are adding starch
# 一定要注意这种地方
Pay attention to spots like these
# 这种地方如果没有抹到位的话
If we haven't spread enough starch here
# 那么它炸的时候首先这里会发干
When deep fried, these parts will become dry
# 然后就是会偏 知道吧
Then they'll be skewed, you know?
# （酱汁）酸甜我们先放这个
Sour and sweet (sauce). We add this first.
# 4勺白醋
Four spoons of white vinegar.
# 番茄酱是甜的 它是甜重于酸
Tamato sauce is sweet. It's more of sweet than sour.
# 所以我们白糖一定要适量一点
So when we add white sugar, the amount must be correct
# 两勺半就够了
Two and a half spoons are enough
# 然后要放一点点盐
Then we add a bit of salt
# 盐放进去是为了中和酸甜味
To balance the sweetness and sourness.
# 把这两个酸跟甜就
So that the sweetness and sourness are...
# （不加盐）让人一吃不是酸就是甜
(Without salt) it tastes either sour only, or sweet only
# 这个加上去的话它是把它们两个
But if we add some salt, then the two of them will...
# 融合在一起
Fuse.
# 把它们两个往中间靠一点
It pushes the two of them towards the middle
# 好 搅好了就开始操作了
OK, it's stirred well, we can start cooking.
# 你们在旁边看 我在那里做
I'll do it here, you guys stand over there and watch.
# 然后我们出了菜之后
And then, after we finish cooking
# 先不要太着急上菜
Do not rush to serve it
# 为什么呢
What’s reason?
# 因为这个鱼炸硬了之后摆起来不是那么好看
Because after deep frying, the fish is tough and the plating doesn't look so good
# 我们在淋汁30秒钟之后还有一次机会
We still have a chance within 30 seconds after pouring the sauce
# 还有一次机会把它摆起来
Another chance for plating
# 看一下啊
Look!
# 刚刚不够立的 现在我们把它立起来摆
It wasn't standing well enough. Now we make it stand well
# 因为它有这个汁水支撑住了
Because now it is supported by the sauce
# 它就可以立得起来
So it can stand well
# 这个时候我们把这个造型摆起来 再上菜的话你可以看
Now we can plate it well, and then serve
# 我随便掐一根 这个我随便掐一根然后蘸点汁
Let me nip off a strip and dip it in the sauce
# 看到没有 一样是脆的
See? It's still crispy
# 听到响吗
Did you hear the sound?
# 嗯
Umm
# 来 试一下吧 直接用手就行
Come on, try it! Just use your hands
# 不用那么讲究
Don't be so delicate
# 吃下这个味道和这个脆度
See how it tastes and how crispy it is
# 这个汁一淋上去 它虽然说挂在表面
Though the sauce is poured over it and covering it
# 但是它浸不进去
It doesn't penetrate
# 浸不进去的话它中间仍然是脆的 知道吧
So the fish is still crispy in the middle, you know
# 嗯 好吃
Umm, delicious.
# 试一下
Try it!
# 我觉得好好吃啊
It tastes so good.
# 油的话 我们后面放的那个油
And also the oil we added in the end
# 边上肯定是要有一层油
There has to be some oil on the sides
# 但这边肯定是多了
But it has to be too much oil on this side
# 看这边 比这边再多一点点就可以了
Look! It should be a little bit more oil than the other side.
# 油也不能太多 知道吧
There shouldn't be too much oil, either, you know
# 好了 剩下的这两条鱼交作业
OK, the remaining two fish are your homework
# 这一条
This one
# 给其它同事吃
Leave it to the other colleagues
# 好 下课
OK, you are dismissed